JEFFREY KAM

hykam@uwaterloo.ca UWaterloo ID: 20716434

INTERESTS

I am interested in graph theory and graph algorithms research, with a particular interest in the graph minor project and graph colouring. In addition, I am also keen on quantum computing and am hoping to explore topics in the intersection of graph theory and quantum computation.

EDUCATION

University of Waterloo

Sep 2017 - Present

Currently in term 4A

- · Candidate for BMath. Combinatorics & Optimizations and Computer Science
- · Minor in Pure Mathematics

Relevant Courses

- · Graph-theoretic Algorithms CS762
- · Algorithms for Graph Minors CO749
- · Algebraic Graph Theory CO444
- · Network Flow Theory CO351
- · Introduction to Graph Theory CO342

Relevant Projects

· Bounded Queue-number in Planar Graphs (CS762) - Project Page

Explore a recent proof by Dujmović et al for a 20-year old conjectjure on whether the queue-number of planar graph is bounded.

· Tangles are Decided by Weighted Vertex Sets (CO749) - Project Page

Explore a partial solution by Elbracht et al to an open problem by Diestel, who asked whether we can find a vertex subset X that can definitively characterize a tangle by seeing which side of a low order separation has more vertices in X. We further explore the possibility improving the weight function to be polynomially-bounded by the number of vertices.

PUBLICATION

· UBCIS: Ultimate Benchmark for Container Image Scanning,

with Shay Berkovich and Glenn Wurster

Published in 13th USENIX Workshop on Cyber Security Experimentation and Test (CSET 20).

https://www.usenix.org/conference/cset20/presentation/berkovich

· bioSyntax: Syntax Highlighting For Computational Biology,

with A. Babaian, et al.

Published in BMC Bioinformatics 19, 303 (2018).

https://doi.org/10.1186/s12859-018-2315-y

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

University of Waterloo - Symbolic Computation Group

May 2020 - Sep 2020

Undergraduate Research Assisstant Supervised by Armin Jamshidpey

Waterloo, Canada

- · Experimented with J-ideal and Smith Normal Form using SAGE
- · Researched different methods to find Smith Normal Form over \mathbb{Z}_{p^2} efficiently, such as probabilistic algorithm
- Read about methods to find normal bases in $\mathbb{F}_{p^n}/\mathbb{F}_p$ and revisited various topics in algebra and Galois theory

BlackBerry - Security Research Group

January 2020 - April 2020

Security Research Intern

Supervised by Shay Berkovich and Glenn Wurster

Waterloo, Canada

- · Researched and designed a universal benchmark to quantitatively measure the effectiveness and accuracy of container image scanners
- · Analyzed techniques of image inspection and vulnerability scanning through open source technologies
- · Designed a universal import framework for Anchore Engine to extend our scanning capabilities
- · Researched on utilizing machine learning for fuzzing algorithmic complexity vulnerabilities (ACV) by reading multiple security-related journals and conference papers
- · Presented to the security research group on current developments of ML-based fuzzing and fuzzing techniques for ACVs, along with potential problems, experiments, and optimizations

WORK EXPERIENCE

GTS Sep 2020 - Present

Software Engineering Intern

New York, US

· Working on performant C++ and Python code for the core trading engine (NDA)

Zenefits
May 2019 - Aug 2019

Software Engineering Intern

Vancouver, Canada

- · Developed new permission services in Django to guard against unauthorized review editing
- · Designed a sequeitial document update service using a distributed messsage queue system

Horizn May 2018 - Aug 2018

Software Developer Intern

Toronto, Canada

- · Wrote automation scripts in Python to scrape data from files and database into JSON files
- · Learned foundational object-oriented programming skills, such as factory and observer pattern

AWARDS

- · First place in HackSeq 2017 bioinformatics competition in UBC
- · Honourable mention in Canadian Computing Competition Hong Kong 2017

SKILLS

Programming Python, C++, SAGE, Scheme

Tools Git, C++ tools (i.e. GCC, GDB, Valgrind), Docker, Linux, Jupyter